ILLIA DANKO

Senior Software Engineer



+48-538-941-416 in illia-danko-608486bb

➤ Kosciuszki 51/2, Street, 78-400 Poland illia-danko

Szczecinek, PL



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Overall, nine years of working experience in the field. Have participated in various technologies and programming languages, including Golang, C, C++, Java, Clojure, Javascript, and Python. Started as a system engineer and was moving to the Web, and Golang, in particular. I'm strongly focused on business' needs, and as a free software user, considering contributing further back to Open Source.

TECH STACK

General Purpose Languages
Golang C Javascript Clojure Python C++ Java
Domain Specific Languages and Frameworks
Bash Makefile CMake Javascript SQL family MongoDB ArangoDB ELisp Lua Elm LTEX
Html Sass & Css React Protobuf

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Aigent

Dec 2019 - Ongoing

- Amsterdam, NL
- Design, develop and maintain core pipeline services.
- Implement internal tools.
- Troubleshooting high performance components.
- Refine existing parts.
- Write technical documentation.
- Collaborate with clients.

Stack

Golang design, prototype, implement and maintain real time low latency microservies using kafka, memcached, rest api, rpcs, protobuf/msgpack, postgresql, arangodb, kubernetes. Write command line tools. Embed C libraries (cgo).

C write ffi libraries for other languages.

Javascript implement ecma5/6 compatible web applications, support react applications. Design, prototype and implement microservices using rest api, protobuf, mqtt, postgresql, kubernetes.

Clojure implement microservices for features using rest api, elasticsearch, mqtt. Implement internal tools.

Python, Bash | ci/cd scripting.

Senior Software Engineer

Omnisend

Feb 2018 - Dec 2019

- Lviv, UA
- Design, develop and maintain high performing services.
- Cover with acceptance and e2e tests.

Stack

Golang design, implement and support features microsevices using rest api, grpc, nats, nsq, mongodb, kubernetes. Integrate 3d party platforms. Write command line tools.

Javascript Design, prototype and implement microservices using rest api, nsq, nats, mongodb.

Python,Bash ci/cd scripting.

Senior Test Engineer

Here

Jun 2017 - Feb 2018

Lviv. UA

- Design and develop integration testing framework.
- Implement and maintain integration tests for car navigation systems.

Stack

Python add features, maintain a testing framework using jenkins, sqlite3, casandra, hadoop map-reduce, aws s3, ec2, route algorithms (djaextra). ci/cd scripting.

Bash | ci/cd scripting.

Middle Software Engineer

Cisco

■ Nov 2015 – Jun 2017

Lviv, UA

- Develop and maintain gateway systems for embedded devices.
- Develop and maintain primitive components and drivers, such as, voip, iptv, vpn.
- Write technical documentation.
- Participate in dmz room setup.
- Maintain and extend dmz testing framework.

Stack

C write and maintain modules for embedded equipment, including character and network devices using pki, httpd, tcp, udp, ppp, cgi, soap, tr-69, tr-98, tr-181, ieee 802.11, ethernet, ipv4, ipv6, dhcp.

Python add features to dmz testing framework using git hooks, jenkins, cisco hardware.

add reduites to diffe testing framework daining gir flooks, jerikins, elseo hardware.

Junior Software Engineer

Inside Secure

Jul 2013 - Nov 2015

Lviv, UA

- Develop and maintain a stereotyped simulator for credit card vendors.
- Write and maintain integration tests.

Stack

C++ implement and support visualization desktop gui tools (qt library), maintain nfs smartcards testing framework.

Java | add features to mastercard nfs smardcards testing framework, maintain tools.

Python, Bash ci/cd scripting.

LANGUAGES

English • • • • •

Ukrainian • • • • • • •

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Economics

Volodymyr Dahl East Ukrainian National University

Sep 2010 - Jun 2013